Joseph Emmanuel

Full Stack Web Developer

4-2314, rue Parthenais, Montreal QC, H1M 2W3

(514) 893-9188

joseph.emmanuel@outlook.com

LinkedIn

GitHub

Portfolio

English, Malayalam, Kannada

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

JavaScript, MySQL, jQuery, PHP, Java, C#, Python, C, C++.

Frameworks:

Laravel 8, Angular, Node.js, WordPress, ASP.NET Core.

IDE:

VS Code, Eclipse, Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, MATLAB, Anaconda, SSMS.

Design Patterns:

MVC, Singleton, observer design.

Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL.

Operating system:

Windows (7/8/10), Linux kali, Tails.

Services:

Docker, Mail-SMTP, IIS, Apache.

Version-control system:

Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, TFS.

Project management tools:

Trello, Asana.

PROFILE

Hard-working and enthusiastic professional with more than 3 years of experience and a reliable knowledge of application development, web platform development, and content design using PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, WordPress and Laravel 8. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the full-stack web developer role at your company.

EXPERIENCE

WEB APPLICATION DEVLOPER

Intuitive Web System, Bangalore, India

2017 - 2018

- Design, build, or maintain web Applications
- Collect user Feedback
- Create database modules
- Solve bugs and run on server
- Implement CI/CD Modules

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Unilog content solutions, Mysore, India

2015 - 2016

- Maintain understanding of current web apps.
- Work programming practices through teamwork.
- Develop or validate test routines
- Schedules run test cases
- Run Test modules.

SOFTWARE TRAINEE

Softend Software Solutions, Kannur, Kerala

2012

- Perform direct web content changes.
- Manage database content.
- Run sample project in different systems.
- Write reports on meetings.
- Replay to the emails from customer.

EDUCATION

Programming And Web Technologies

ISI - L'INSTITUT SUPÉRIEUR D'INFORMATIQUE, Montreal, QC (2019-present)

Computer Science and Engineering Master of Technology

VTU-Bangalore, India (2017)

Computer Science and Engineering Bachelor of Technology

CUFE - Bangalore, India (2014)

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Sous chef

NextDoor Pub & Grill, Montreal, QC 2019 - Present

- Assure quality and cleanliness of the food.
- Ensure freshness of food and ingredients.
- Pay attention to detail when sending out a food item.

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST

PROJECTS

WHISTLER - PHP, LARAVEL 8, MYSOL AND SOCIALITE

- According to the user needs the application will track and update the job applications made online
- I worked in a team of five people, working as a full stack developer. My work was to design migrations and working on the backend.
- Link: Whistler

SMARTO- ANDROID APP

- The app provides a game for general knowledge about pop culture, history.
- I worked solo in this project and my work was to design and implement the software.
- Link: **SmartQ**

Loan Prediction - | Python, Anaconda, Pandas, Matplotlib

- According to the input data the prediction will be produced if
- they are met the criteria.
- I worked alone as a hobby project idea I found online.
- Link: Loan Prediction

PUZZLER - | JS, HTML5, CSS3, MYSOL

- Puzzler is a memory enhancement app and uses a 'spaced repetition' technique to help users memorize designs.
- I worked alone to create an app and design application in a short period of time.
- Link: Puzzler

Social Sign App - | PHP, HTML5, CSS3, MvSOL, XAMPP

- An app where people can normally go to sign petitions to stop wars and change the world.
- I worked in a group of two people and I worked on both front-end and back-end
- Link : Social Sign App

Courier Services | C#, XML, MSSOL, TFS, Azure, .net Core

- Vendors can schedule pickup for courier services up on request from user.
- I worked in a team of two people working as a full stack developer. My work was to design, implement scheduling the pickup and take user experience in account to improve the UI/UX design of the application.
- Link: copyrighted product